<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Professional Projects on Agent Arachnids Anthology</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/professional-projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Professional Projects on Agent Arachnids Anthology</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 14:27:52 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/professional-projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Unannounced</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/professional-projects/unannounced/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 14:27:52 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/professional-projects/unannounced/</guid>
      <description>This project is yet to be announced, but since it is my own project I&amp;rsquo;m more than happy and able to share about my involvement.&#xA;Role: Lead Developer In this personal project, I’ve taken on multiple roles, including programmer, designer, modeller, and project manager. Over the past year, I have been dedicated to creating a social deduction game set in Victorian London, inspired by titles like Among Us. As the sole developer, I’ve been responsible for building every aspect of the game, with a strong focus on technical implementation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GoldenTides</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/professional-projects/goldentides/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 14:27:41 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/professional-projects/goldentides/</guid>
      <description>Role: Unreal Engineer In my role as an Unreal Engineer for Golden Tides, I was tasked with designing and implementing code to meet both technical requirements and gameplay goals. A primary focus was ensuring that the code could scale effectively and maintain functionality within multiplayer environments. Although I had limited prior experience with networking in Unreal Engine, I embraced this challenge, growing significantly as a developer throughout the project.&#xA;Multiplayer Networking Despite being new to Unreal Engine&amp;rsquo;s networking systems at the start, I quickly adapted and implemented multiplayer features that supported seamless gameplay.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AUDL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/professional-projects/audl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 14:27:36 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/professional-projects/audl/</guid>
      <description>Role: Gameplay Developer at Ultix Technology In my role at Ultix Technology, I have been instrumental in the development of key gameplay systems, focusing on both single-player and multiplayer functionality. By balancing technical precision and creativity, I ensure seamless user experiences across different game modes. My expertise extends beyond development, enabling me to lead and mentor team members on best practices and innovative approaches in Unreal Engine.&#xA;Unreal Engine (C++ and Blueprints) I utilize both C++ and Unreal Engine Blueprints, allowing me to optimize the workflow and accelerate design iteration.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
